# Naimish Mani B.

# Mechanical Engineer | Data Scientist



naimish240.github.io



naimish240



maimish-balaji



naimish240@gmail.com

## Bio

I am a Mechanical Engineering graduate from SASTRA University. I have experience with Numerical Methods, Backend Development, Machine Learning and CFD. I enjoy working on interdisciplinary projects where I can learn about various domains and expand my knowledge.

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### **EMSEC PVT LTD** R&D CONSULTANT

Aug 2023 - Present | Remote

- → Wrote ODE and PDE solvers in SciPy to solve real-world problems numerically.
- → Designed UI Wireframes and closely monitored the development of the GUI products that interfaced with the numerical solvers.
- → Led weekly scrum meetings and wrote internal documentation for the products.

#### **DELOITTE USI** ANALYST

Nov 2022 - July 2023 | Mumbai

- → Helped condense client requirements into a curated list of actionable items for the development team, saving weeks of effort.
- → Conducted in-depth analysis of existing Integrated Eligibility Systems (IES) solutions to identify and address inefficiencies.
- → Designed and developed RESTful APIs to convert monolithic IES systems into microservices using SpringBoot.

# **PROJECTS**

#### SEMI SUPERVISED CLASSIFICATION OF IMAGES SHOT BY CURIOSITY ROVER

PYTHON, TENSORFLOW, SCIKIT LEARN, NUMPY, PILLOW

- → Used a Deep Convolutional Autoencoder to generate latent space representations of the images.
- → Visualized the latent vectors with t-SNE and iterated through different architectures till the network learnt useful features.
- → Used a Support Vector Machine to classify the latent space representations, achieving 94 % accuracy.

# GROUND BASED CLOUD CLASSIFICATION USING CNNS TFLITE, JUPYTER, ANDROID, 10.S

- → Designed and trained a CNN with TensorFlow Lite for ground based cloud classification, and achieved an accuracy of around 70%.
- → Exported the model into an Android and iOS app, deployed the same.

# USING NLP TECHNIQUES TO IDENTIFY BIAS IN HUMAN SPEECH SCIKIT LEARN,

- FLASK, SHAP, HEROKU
  - → Built an NLP model to identify if a statement is objective or subjective, used Shapley analysis to interpret the model.
  - → Deployed the model with Flask on Heroku, and hosted the frontend on GitHub Pages. Set up CORS to allow resource sharing between the two platforms.

# SKILLS

#### **PROGRAMMING**

Pvthon • MATLAB • C++ • C SQL • R • Java

#### **TOOLS**

GitHub • Trello • Docker AWS • Tableau • GitFlow

# **CERTIFICATION**

Google Data Analytics Professional Certificate AWS Certified Developer Associate

#### **EDUCATION**

# SASTRA DEEMED TO BE UNIVERSITY

BACHELOR OF TECHNOLOGY, MECHANICAL ENGINEERING July 2018 - July 2022 | Thanjavur, India School of Mechanical Engineering

## EXTRA CURRICULARS

President, Stellaria, the Space Club of SASTRA

Head of Web Development, Google's DSC - SASTRA

# **COURSEWORK**

#### UNDERGRADUATE

- Production, Planning and
- Systems Modelling, Dynamics and Control
- Numerical and Statistical Methods
- Operations Research
- Industrial Robotics

## ACHIEVEMENTS

Finalist, Ad'Venture Pitch Fest • Speaker, DST-INSPIRE Camp • XPRIZE Visioneering design challenge Wiki winner